Hello there, it's Yorky and welcome to the channel for the 10th episode of the in-depth
track guide series for a setter coaster competition journey.
And just quickly before we get into all the juicy details that are going to help you improve
your lap times around this circuit, if you're new to the channel and enjoying this in-depth
track guide series then please consider subscribing to the channel, it will be very much appreciated.
If you want to follow me on other social media pages my links are down in description
below.
So for this 10th episode we are going to be taking a look at Barcelona Catalonia in Spain.
The circuit itself comes out to 2.89 miles which is 4.65 kilometers and features 16 turns.
The setup that you want to be using for the circuit should be run about medium downforce
with medium suspension stiffness and then the key action areas where there's possibility
for overtaking will be turns 1, turns 4, 5, 7 and turn 10.
Next up we're going to take a look at the pit entry and the pit exit and the entrance
to the pit lane is just between the penultimate corner and the final corner just before you
turn the car into that turn 16.
It's there on the inside you may need to slow a little bit as you come into the pit
lane and then you will need to slow down and get the car engaged onto the pit limiter.
About 70 or 80 meters before the end of the white concrete wall that's there on the inside
this is where the pit limiter line is actually situated and then at the other end of the
pit lane the pit exit is right next to the Barcelona Martial Hut that you can see situated
here.
At this point you want to disengage the pit limiter and accelerate out, down, back, out
onto the circuit.
The pit exit line actually extends pretty far down towards turn 1 so make sure you step
to the right of that when coming out of the pit lane.
So we're going to move on to the track itself and we're obviously going to be starting
off with the breaking point for the first corner.
It's about 120 meters before the turn we're going to be breaking hard and shifting down
into second gear.
We're then going to turn the car in towards our first apex aiming to clip the inside
curve which you can use in the dry conditions.
You want to be careful with it in the wet conditions.
The curve as you can see is serrated and there is a slight sloshish curve on the inside
here so you want to be careful of that.
But coming off the exit of turn 1 which you'll want to sacrifice, we're immediately coming
into turn 2.
This is going to be your typical apex point.
Some cars will allow you to use the inside curve but others you'll need to be very cautious
with in both the dry and wet conditions as again quite easily unsettle the car.
But as we come out the exit of turn 2, we don't want to run all the way over to the right
hand side of the circuit where there's that painted tarmac and the astroturfing want
to stay just shy of that to try and open up turn 3 which pretty much immediately follows.
You're going to turn the car in whilst on full throttle and as we come through the corner
you'll need to lift a little bit and close the car through the turn to try and keep it
hooked up towards the inside.
And then as you progress through the turn just off the inside curve as soon as you see
a second set of orange painted tire barriers on the outside that is when you want to be
getting full throttle and accelerating out through the exit.
Right here there is plenty of tarmac to run off onto.
You need to keep two wheels on the red and white curving to stay within track limits.
You can use this in the dry conditions however you want to be very cautious in the wet
potentially avoid it if entirely possible.
But we're going to stay out here to the left of the circuit ready for the braking zone
of turn 4 which is just before we get to the bridge at the large white line that's just
to the left of the track.
We're going to brake heavily at this point and shift down into first or second gear
aiming for a very early apex where we're going to just brush the curve on the inside
there and run the car a tiny little bit deep and then we're going to try and bring it
back a little bit towards a second later apex as we continue to accelerate and turn through
the corner.
As we're coming off the exit of turn 4 though we don't actually want to run all the
way out towards this exit curving.
You can use it in the dry conditions if you want but you want to avoid it in the wet
conditions as the rumble strip nature of it will cost you the traction but what you want
to do is bring the car immediately back over towards the right hand side of the track ready
to open up turn 5 and this is our braking point.
There's no real reference in and around here so it's pretty much just down to getting
the flow and using your pure judgement for this corner.
So turning in at apex it's actually going to be fairly late in the turn.
You want to get fairly close to the inside curve you can use it in the dry conditions although
you want to be very cautious with it in the wet conditions but you want to focus on
getting a good drive coming off the exit of the turn where we're going to use as much
of the curve as we possibly can on the exit.
You want to keep at least two wheels on the red and white curving in order to stay within
track limits however in the wet conditions you'll be wanting to avoid the curve entirely
to not cost you any traction.
Turn 6 is pretty much nonexistent so we then come into the braking zone for turn 7
and we're going to reference the start of the curving there on the right hand side of
the track as our braking point.
We're going to shift the car down into second gear and actually carry a little bit more
speed coming into our apex than you would initially anticipate.
In the dry conditions you can use this inside slope curve pretty much no problem however
you'll want to be cautious with it in the wet conditions but as we come out 3d exit
we're getting hard on the throttle we're immediately coming into turn 8 and we want
to try and take as much off the inside here as we possibly can.
There is a row of intermittent sausage curbs on the inside here and some cars may not
like you bumping over that but if your car is good at taking curbs then use this in the
dry conditions keep two wheels on the red and white curving to stay within track limits
however you'll probably want to avoid all this curving pretty much entirely in the wet
conditions as the wet slippery curbs will cost you the run going up the hill towards
turn 9.
This is going to be our braking point for the fast right hander at the top of the hill
here it's just at the end of the red and white curving on the left hand side it's going
to be a short dab of the brake and then we're going to turn the car in and let it flow through
the corner.
We're going to apex roughly about midway through the turn we're going to be using third
or fourth gear as a slight bit of camber through this turn as well you want to be cautious
with this corner in that you don't really want to be using the curving on the inside
in either the dry or wet conditions and you dry you can get away with brushing the
curbs some cars may allow you to actually mount it but the majority of them you'll be
willing to stay off it and instead focus on getting a good exit where out here we're
going to use as much of the curving as we can possibly get away with stay with two wheels
on that red and white serrated curving in order to stay within track limits don't venture
out past that onto the FIA green curving that's out there and obviously in the wet conditions
like many exit curbs you'll be willing to avoid this curving pretty much entirely.
Next up is the final potential overtaking opportunity which is the break in zone for turn
10.
We're going to be breaking about 120 meters before the corner there is a 100 meter board
there to reference on the right hand side of the track we're going to shift in all
the way down into first gear and turn in the car in in both the dry and wet conditions
you should be able to take plenty of the inside curve here you just need to make sure that
you do get the car slowed down as this corner does feature some adverse camber which means
that the track is kind of falling away from you you'll make it more difficult to actually
stay hooked in towards the turn and you need to get that rotation because the exit does
tighten up on you you can use the exit curving out here there is a yellow sausage curve that
runs pretty much the length of the exit of turn 10 so do be mindful of that as actually
dipping your outside wheels over across that can potentially unsettle the car and make
it a little bit more difficult in trying to apply the power obviously in the wet conditions
avoid this exit curve pretty much at all costs we then come into turn 11 no breaking
zone for this corner it's literally flat out just check the car in try and take as much
of the inside curve as you possibly there just to try and cut off as many meters off the
circuit as you possibly can and then we pretty much immediately come into turn 12 it's
going to be a very short breaking zone before we actually start to turn the car in and we're
going to actually trail break as we turn into the corner as well our apex point is going
to be mid to late in the turn you basically just want to hug that inside curve all the
way through the corner be careful with it in the dry conditions as a can sometimes unsettle
the car and obviously avoid it in the wet conditions but when we come out through the exit
we're going to use the exit curve that is out here although there isn't too much space
beyond it so make sure that you don't dip your wheels too far out our out into the gravel
obviously use it in the dry conditions however do avoid it in the wet and rainy conditions
and then we come into the breaking zone for turn 13 again light turn five there's no
real reference point for the breaking zone coming into this corner is literally just
basically judged off of feel and general flow but when we turn the car in we're going
to aim to apex here on the red and white serrated curve which we can use in both the dry
and wet conditions what we need to be careful of is the large sausage curve on the inside
here we do not want to be clipping that as that will very heavily unsettle the car and
then when we come out through the exit whilst we want to try and maximize the width of
the track we don't actually want to be running out onto the curb on the outside here so try
and avoid it in both the dry and wet conditions as what we'll need to do is try and bring the
car back as far right to open up the breaking zone for turns 14 and 15 this is going to
be our breaking point just before we get to the gantry that extends over the circuit we're
going to shift the car down into first gear and turn into the first of the two apexes
for the chicane both of the two apexes should be on the red and white rumble strip curbing
you want to avoid the large red sausage curbs on the inside of both apexes as clipping
these will bounce and unsettle the car and likely take you off the ideal line that you
want to be taking in order to get through the chicane smoothly coming out 3d exit of
the chicane we got a sun-concerated curb to contend with along with a long yellow sausage
curve that is there in the dry conditions a number of drivers and cars will be able
to take this curve to try and maximize the speed coming off of the corner you want to
avoid it in the wet conditions as the slippery painted surfaces will cost you the traction
and then we come into the final corner itself turns 16 there's no breaking zone for this
corner so it's literally just trying to take a nice smooth line coming through the
turn we're going to clip the apex at midway point we're going to stay off the inside
curve coming through the corners it can potentially unsettle the car in both the dry and also
the wet conditions and then as we come out 3d exit what to unwind the wheel keep your foot
fully planted maximize the exit curbing out here staying with two wheels on that red
and white serrated curve because extending over that we'll see you infringing track limits
and obviously in the wet conditions you'll probably want to be avoiding this curve pretty
much entirely as it will likely light up the rear tires and then cost you the run to
the start finish line to complete your lap so now that we've done a breakdown of all
the corners let's jump in the car and see how it looks piece together
so now that we've finished a semi-decent lap around Catalonia I just want to finish off the
episode by saying please be mindful of what your car and car setup is capable of some cars
will be able to break a little bit later than others some cars will be able to take curves better
than others so obviously going to be dependent on your car setup might have a slight factor as
well and then obviously the weather conditions are going to play a factor too obviously I've tried
to highlight these things where possible but please do take note and obviously apply accordingly
to the session race or conditions that you're driving in other than that thank you very much for
watching the episode if you enjoyed it please give it a like and if you want to support the
channel please consider subscribing and if you hit the bell notification you'll be notified each
time a video goes live and you won't miss out on any future content I hope to see you back for
the next one until then have fun stay safe and take care